<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soft Skills on xiantang - Self-discipline set me free.</title>
    <link>https://vim0.com/en/categories/soft-skills/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soft Skills on xiantang - Self-discipline set me free.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 21:33:31 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vim0.com/en/categories/soft-skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Settling in Singapore After Physically Crossing the Wall</title>
      <link>https://vim0.com/en/post/singapore_3_month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 21:33:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vim0.com/en/post/singapore_3_month/</guid>
      <description>What can you get from reading this article This article mainly talks about some things you need to do after coming to work in Singapore. By reading this article, you can get some necessary things you need to do after landing in Singapore, such as renting a house, applying for a bank card, etc., to prevent everyone from stepping into pitfalls.
Renting a House The first important thing after coming to work in Singapore is to rent a house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Worker&#39;s Recent Half-Year Experience in Learning and Practicing Fund Investment Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://vim0.com/en/post/investment/learned_about_investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 20:55:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vim0.com/en/post/investment/learned_about_investment/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Everyone should invest, the sooner the better. Even if you keep losing money, at least you will learn how to lose less after ten years. Instead of waiting until ten years later when you are forced to invest, you lose most of your principal at once&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;@xiaodotdo
 Preface Because I stepped into work from school, I was actually a bit richer than when I was studying, and I was also quite frugal, so I had a lot of money left every month when I got paid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to Physically Crossing the Wall to Singapore During the Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://vim0.com/en/post/softskills/physical_break_gfw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 14:40:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vim0.com/en/post/softskills/physical_break_gfw/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The difficulty of living abroad is smaller than imagined, but the determination needed to go abroad is greater than imagined&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;@FreiheitYu The author wrote this article in early 2021, and there may be discrepancies due to the relaxation and tightening of immigration policies, for reference only. Preface This is a very struggling and bumpy experience. Under the situation of the pandemic, I still chose to come out from my country</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Skills: A Guide for Lower-Level Employees in Big Companies</title>
      <link>https://vim0.com/en/post/softskills/how_to_live_in_big_company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 14:40:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vim0.com/en/post/softskills/how_to_live_in_big_company/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I found that many articles and interviews are about how to get into big companies, but actually surviving in big companies is also a skill&amp;rdquo;
 Preface The author recently changed jobs, chose to follow his heart, and did not continue to work in the previous company. Taking advantage of the recent resignation, I quickly calmed down and output my previous experience. Although I only stayed in the previous company for almost a year (the previous company referred to in this article is a certain company), I still learned some of the working methods and processes of big companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Skills: How do I acquire knowledge and information?</title>
      <link>https://vim0.com/en/post/softskills/how_do_i_acquire_knowledge_and_information/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 14:40:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vim0.com/en/post/softskills/how_do_i_acquire_knowledge_and_information/</guid>
      <description>​ &amp;ldquo;We are all hunters in the wilderness of the information age, surviving in the vast wilderness of information.&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Why Become an Information Predator&amp;rdquo;
​ In the era of mobile internet with information explosion, every internet giant is trying to build their own &amp;ldquo;information cocoon&amp;rdquo;, trying to recommend you some things you are interested in, and gradually your life will be shackled in a cocoon-like cage. As a [hacker] who yearns for freedom, naturally, he cannot be restricted by such a cage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
